John C. Hood II

in: john-hood-462a9881

: JohnChood2

↑: johnchood2.github.io

✓: hood.astro@gmail.com

Observational astrophysicist searching for correlated variabilities in multi wavelength observations of Active Galactic Nuclei and experimental cosmologist with 4+ years of experience with experimental cosmology and 3 years of experience with millimeter-wavelength data analysis using the SPTpol 500 square degree field. I am highly organized, self-motivated, and a creative thinker.

EDUCATION

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

• Ph.D. Astrophysics; Advisers: Kelly Holley-Bockelmann, Stephan Meyer Title: CMB Detector Development and Astronomical People watching 08/17 - 08/22

Fisk University

Nashville, TN, USA

• M.A. Physics; Adviser: Jedidah Isler

08/15 - 08/17

Title: The Search for Orphan Flares via Multi-waveband Observations of Fermi Bright Blazars

Columbus State University

Columbus, GA, USA

B.Sc. degree in Astrophysics and Planetary Geology; Minors: Physics, Geology and Robotics

08/09 - 05/14

2014-2018

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Experimental Cosmology and Astrophysics
- Active Galactic Nuclei
- Multi-wavelength Variability Correlations
- Machine Learning / Artificial Intelligence
- Cosmic Microwave Background

SKILLS

- Machine tools/ applications
- proficient in Python
- proficient in data visualization
- proficient in LaTeX
- adept in IRAF
- adept in GDSpy

Honors and Awards

- SCGSR Fellowship accepted
- GAANN Fellowship
- Dunlap Institute Instrumentation Summer School Travel Award
- Bridge Graduate Research Fellowship
- Larry M. Pollatta Student Acheivement Award
- Georgia Institute of Museum and Library Services IMLS Grant
- Georgia Space Grant

Professional Society Memberships

• Member, American Astronomical Society

• Member, National Society of Black Physicists	2017-2019
• Student Member, Sigma Xi	2017-2019
• Society of Amateur Radio Astronomers SARA	2015-2019

SCIENTIFIC COLLABORATIONS AND COMMUNITIES

• Member, South Pole Telescope Group	2018-present
• Member, CMB-S4	2019-present
Teaching and Public Outreach	
Science Liaison with SPT First Discoveries Program	2020-present
• ARP Argonne ACT-SO student mentor	2020-2021
• Adler Planetarium ask a scientist volunteer presenter	2018-present
• Space Explorers instructor	2018-2019
• School for Science and Math at Vanderbilt (SSMV), Robotics and astronomy instructor	2016-2018
• Pulsar Search Collaboratory, Mentor	2016
• Mobile planetarium instructor and operator, Columbus State University	2013-2015
• Astronomy night telescope operator, Columbus State University	2011-2014
Observing Experience	
• 1 month of experience operating and maintaining the 10m South Pole Telescope	Winter 2019
• 200 hours of deep sky surveying; West Rock Observatory's 0.6m telescope	2013 - 2015
$\bullet~500+~\mathrm{hours}$ of solar monitoring; West Rock Observatory's 0.6m telescope	2011 - 2015
Positions Held	
Mead WestVaco Observatory Technician, Coca-Cola Space Science Center	2014-2015
• Education and Outreach Coordinator, Coca-Cola Space Science Center	2012-2015
Contributed Talks/Posters	

Contributed Talks/Posters

- Low loss microstrip materials for microwave applications: for the South Pole Telescope; Fisk-Vanderbilt
 Bridge Research Celebration Day
 Talk, 2021
- Alumni spotlight presentation; Coca-Cola Space Science Center 20th Anniversary Ceremony Talk, 2019
- Design and Implementation of a Polarization Sensitive Antenna Centered at 90GHz; CMB-S4 Collaboration Meeting
 Poster, 2019
- Columbus State University: Underrepresented Groups in the Earth, Environmental and Space Sciences: A
 Panel Discussion with Alumni and Students from Columbus State University's Department of Earth and
 Space Sciences
 panelist, 2020
- Columbus State University: ESS Seminar; Optical Gamma-Ray "Orphan Flares" and SMARTS Fermi-Bright Blazars
 Talk, 2018
- Hood, J. et al. A Search for Optical and Gamma-ray "Orphan Flares" in the SMARTS Sample of Fermi-Bright Blazars", 230th AAS Meeting (Poster 44), Austin Texas Poster, 2017
- Hood, J. et al. CSU's MWV Observatory: A Facility for Research, Education and Outreach. American Astronomical Society Meeting Abstracts #223, 223, 446.01. Poster, 2014
- **Hood, J.** et al. (2014) "Da-Klaw, Columbus State Universities Robotic Hand" project talk at the ICRAR, Florida International University, Miami, Florida

 Talk, 2014
- Perry, M., McCarty, C., Bartow, M., **Hood, J.**., Lodder, K., Johnson, M., Cruzen, S. T., Williams, R. N. Columbus State University Global Observation and Outreach for the 2012 Transit of Venus. American Astronomical Society Meeting Abstracts #221, 221, 433.03.

 Poster, 2013
- Johnson, M., **Hood, J.**, Williams, R. N. M., Cruzen, S., Johnson, C. Mead Observatory WebCasts: Public Outreach to the World. American Astronomical Society Meeting Abstracts #215, 215, 468.06. **Poster, 2010**
- Johnson, M., Hood, J., Cruzen, S. T., Williams, R. N. M. (2007). RISO: A New Online Tool for Bringing the Sun into the Classroom. American Astronomical Society Meeting Abstracts, 211, 70.02. Poster, 2007
- Johnson, M., **Hood, J.**, Cruzen, S. T. Solar Education and Outreach at Columbus State University's Mead Observatory. American Astronomical Society Meeting Abstracts, 209, 94.05. **Poster, 2006**

- **Hood**, **J.** et al. Correlated Variability of PKS 2326-502 from Millimeter to γ -Ray's: SPTpol 500 square degree field AGN monitoring (**in prep**)
- J. Hood, P. Barry, T. Cecil, C. Chang, S. Meyer, J. Li, Z.Pan, E. Shirokoff, and A. Tang, (2022). Testing low-loss microstrip materials with mkids for microwave applications, ArXiv E-Prints, arXiv:2202.00115.
- Cecil, T., Barry, P., Bender, A., Chang, C., Czaplewski, D., Hood, J., Kuhlmann, S., Lisovenko, M., Meyer, S., Novosad, V., Wang, G., Yefremenko, V., Zhang, J. (2021). OMT-Coupled CMB Detector Development at Argonne. IEEE Transactions on Applied Superconductivity, 31(5), 3065270. https://doi.org/10.1109/TASC.2021.3065270
- Guns, S., Foster, A., Daley, C., Rahlin, A., Whitehorn, N., Ade, P. A. R., Ahmed, Z., Anderes, E., Anderson, A. J., Archipley, M., Avva, J. S., Aylor, K., Balkenhol, L., Barry, P. S., Basu Thakur, R., Benabed, K., Bender, A. N., Benson, B. A., Bianchini, F., Hood, J., ... Zhang, L. (2021). Detection of Galactic and Extragalactic Millimeter-wavelength Transient Sources with SPT-3G., 916(2), 98. https://doi.org/10.3847/1538-4357/ac06a3
- Dutcher, D., Balkenhol, L., Ade, P. A. R., Ahmed, Z., Anderes, E., Anderson, A. J., Archipley, M., Avva, J. S., Aylor, K., Barry, P. S., Basu Thakur, R., Benabed, K., Bender, A. N., Benson, B. A., Bianchini, F., Bleem, L. E., Bouchet, F. R., Bryant, L., Byrum, K., Hood, J., ... SPT-3G Collaboration. (2021). Measurements of the E-mode polarization and temperature-E-mode correlation of the CMB from SPT-3G 2018 data., 104(2), 22003. https://doi.org/10.1103/PhysRevD.104.022003
- Sobrin, J. A., Anderson, A. J., Bender, A. N., Benson, B. A., Dutcher, D., Foster, A., Goeckner-Wald, N., Montgomery, J., Nadolski, A., Rahlin, A., Ade, P. A. R., Ahmed, Z., Anderes, E., Archipley, M., Austermann, J. E., Avva, J. S., Aylor, K., Balkenhol, L., Barry, P. S., ... Young, M. R. (2021). The Design and Integrated Performance of SPT-3G. ArXiv E-Prints, arXiv:2106.11202.
- Montgomery, J., Ade, P. A. R., Ahmed, Z., Anderes, E., Anderson, A. J., Archipley, M., Avva, J. S., Aylor, K., Balkenhol, L., Barry, P. S., Basu Thakur, R., Benabed, K., Bender, A. N., Benson, B. A., Bianchini, F., Bleem, L. E., Bouchet, F. R., Bryant, L., Byrum, K., Hood, J., ... Young, M. R. (2021). Performance and characterization of the SPT-3G digital frequency-domain multiplexed readout system using an improved noise and crosstalk model. ArXiv E-Prints, arXiv:2103.16017.
- Balkenhol, L., Dutcher, D., Ade, P. A. R., Ahmed, Z., Anderes, E., Anderson, A. J., Archipley, M., Avva, J. S., Aylor, K., Barry, P. S., Basu Thakur, R., Benabed, K., Bender, A. N., Benson, B. A., Bianchini, F., Bleem, L. E., Bouchet, F. R., Bryant, L., Byrum, K., Hood, J., ... Young, M. R. (2021). Constraints on CDM Extensions from the SPT-3G 2018 *EE* and *TE* Power Spectra. ArXiv E-Prints, arXiv:2103.13618.
- The CMB-S4 Collaboration, Abazajian, K., Addison, G. E., Adshead, P., Ahmed, Z., Akerib, D., Ali, A., Allen, S. W., Alonso, D., Alvarez, M., Amin, M. A., Anderson, A., Arnold, K. S., Ashton, P., Baccigalupi, C., Bard, D., Barkats, D., Barron, D., Hood, J., ... Zonca, A. (2020). CMB-S4: Forecasting Constraints on Primordial Gravitational Waves. ArXiv E-Prints, arXiv:2008.12619.

ACADEMIC REFERENCES

• References available upon request